Guide to the Sarah Refo Mason Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Canton YMCA Research Materials, Series II
  - Correspondence with Frank Leung, Alice Jim, and others planning visit to Canton YMCA, 1990s (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence with Helen Sun and Dorthy Jimru (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Research on Maud Russell: YMCA Missionary 1917 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Paper - "Between Social Salvation and Cultural Imperialism", 1991 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Research materials, 1988-1991 (Box 12, Folder 73)
  - Index for Annual Reports of Canton YMCA, 1913-1919 (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Chinese Articles on Canton YMCA (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - Review of Jun Xing book, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 76)
  - Photos (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - Interview with General Secretary George Wong (Wong Yidun) (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - George Wong correspondence and articles, 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - Notes on George Wong (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence with Samuel Shao (Shao Mingyao), 1982-1989 (Box 13, Folder 81)
  - Ed Lockwood articles and reports, 1930-1940s (Box 13, Folder 82)
  - Ed Lockwood files from archives, 1930-1940s (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - Ed Lockwood articles and papers, 1920s-1930s (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence with Harry Brunger, 1980-1990s (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - Harry Brunger: reports and journal, 1940-1950s (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - Reports and papers of S. C. Leung 1920 Gen Sec. of YMCA-First Chinese (Box 13, Folder 87)
  - William Lockwood: Papers, Peter Yeo dissertation on Lockwood, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 88)
  - Orrin Magill papers and notes (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - Missionaries H-J's: Hayes-Leiser (Box 14, Folder 90a)
  - Y.L. Lee-report on Labor situation in Canto, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 90b)
  - Y.L. Lee-articles, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 91)
  - Canton YMCA publications in Chinese (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - Canton YMCA documents and reports, 1910-1940s (Box 15, Folder 93-98)
  - Canton YMCA early history (Box 15, Folder 99)
  - Canton YMCA background articles and reports, 1920-1930s (Box 16, Folder 100)
  - Canton YMCA interview notes, 1990s (Box 16, Folder 101)
  - Canton YMCA Photos and correspondence (Box 16, Folder 102)
  - Canton YMCA Publications in Chinese (Box 16, Folder 103)
  - Elsie Anderson's books (YWCA worker in Canton in the 1920s - also involved with True Light Middle School and women students at Lingnan) (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - Music collection of Elsie Anderson (Box 17, Folder 105)
  - Publications by Ethel and Walworth Tyng (Box 17, Folder 106)
  - Publications by Mary Tyng Higgins (Box 17, Folder 107)
  - Photo album of Elsie Anderson (photos of YWCA, True Light MIddle School) (Box 17, Folder 108)
  - Canton YMCA: photos, 1990 (Box 36, Folder 354)
  - YMCA misc. correspondence (Box 36, Folder 355)
  - YMCA references: the Christian Century (Box 36, Folder 356)
  - YMCA Hong Kong: Agape (Box 36, Folder 357)
  - Daniel C. Fu, "New Trends in the YMCA", 1941 (Box 36, Folder 358)
  - Canton YMCA notes (Box 36, Folder 359)
  - Canton YMCA misc. documentation (Box 36, Folder 360)
  - Tse King Suen Guangzhou YMCA (Box 36, Folder 361)
  - Lingnan University (Box 36, Folder 362)
  - Canton YMCA references: Chinese Recorder (Box 36, Folder 363)
  - Canton YMCA materials (Box 36, Folder 364)
  - Articles by Eugene E. Barnett (Box 36, Folder 365)
  - Sherwood Eddy, "The Social Gospel in China"; Sidney L. Gulick, "The Church and a Warless World"; William A. Mather, "Achievement in Self-support", 1923 (Box 36, Folder 366)
  - Garrett notes (Box 36, Folder 367)
  - Richard P. Madsen, "The Student Christian Movement and Chinese Nationalism: 1927-1937" (Box 37, Folder 368)
  - Rhoads Murphy, "Observations on War in China, 1942-1946", 1995 (Box 37, Folder 369)
  - YMCA misc. (Box 37, Folder 370)
  - YMCA archives--University of Minnesota (Box 37, Folder 371)
  - Canton YMCA: Proposals (Box 40, Folder 439)
  - Canton YMCA: Chung Ming Kwong (Box 40, Folder 440)
- True Light Middle School Research Materials, Series III
  - Photos; see also Elsie Anderson photo album, Box 17, Folder 108 (Box 17, Folder 109a)
  - History 1872-1967 (Box 17, Folder 109b)
  - History documents, 1920s (Box 18, Folder 110)
  - 50th year - yearbook (Box 18, Folder 111)
  - Publications (Box 18, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence with alumni, 1981-1999, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 113-115)
  - Correspondence with Shus (Box 18, Folder 116)
  - Faculty: Ruth Craft (Box 18, Folder 117)
  - Faculty: Fairies - Fisher (Box 19, Folder 118)
  - Faculty: Howell - McPherson (Pomerenke) (Box 19, Folder 119)
  - Faculty: Jean McPherson (Pomerenke) letters, 1917-1926 (Box 19, Folder 120-121)
  - Faculty: Noyes - "A Light in the Land" (Box 19, Folder 122)
  - Faculty: Noyes Letters (Box 19, Folder 123)
  - Former students: interview tapes (Box 19, Folder 124)
  - Former students: interview notes, 1993-1995 (Box 20, Folder 125)
  - True Light and other missionary schools for young women: notes, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 441)
- Women in China Missions Research Materials, Series IV
  - Schools for girls in China (Box 20, Folder 126)
  - Mary Nelson Denison taped interview (Box 20, Folder 127)
  - Photos of Mei-Wa School (Box 20, Folder 128)
  - Publications of Mei-Wa School (Box 20, Folder 129)
  - Nelson Family articles and letters (Box 20, Folder 130)
  - Nelson family letters (Box 20, Folder 131)
  - Charles Nelson later correspondence, 1940s (Box 20, Folder 132)
  - Notes on women missionaries, 1990s (Box 20, Folder 133)
  - Articles on women missionaries, 1980s-1990s (Box 21, Folder 134)
  - Articles on women missionaries, 1930s-1990s (Box 21, Folder 135)
  - Articles on female social roles (Box 21, Folder 136)
  - Articles on women in China missions:, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 137)
  - Articles on effects of missionaries, 1920s-1970s (Box 21, Folder 138)
  - Articles evaluating missions work in China, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 139)
  - Women in China Missions: A - M (Box 21, Folder 140)
  - Women in China Missions: Smythe-China Missions Oral project (Box 21, Folder 141)
  - Women in China Missions: N -T (Box 22, Folder 142)
- Lingnan University Research Materials, Series V
  - Science Journal Vol. 14 and 15, 1935-1936 (Box 22, Folder 143)
  - Photos (Box 22, Folder 144)
  - Articles from Archives (Box 22, Folder 145)
  - Historical Publications (Box 22, Folder 146)
  - Alumni Magazine, 1992-1993 (Box 22, Folder 147)
  - Interview with Henry Refo and Borodin (Box 23, Folder 148)
  - Articles, 1918 (Box 23, Folder 149)
  - Publications, 1989-1990 (Box 23, Folder 150)
  - Interviews with students (Box 23, Folder 151)
  - Alumni Directory (Box 23, Folder 152)
  - Faculty: William Augur articles (Box 23, Folder 153)
  - Faculty: William Augur-correspondence, 1980-86 (Box 23, Folder 154)
  - Faculty: articles and corespondence (Box 23, Folder 155)
  - Faculty: J. Fisher (Box 24, Folder 156)
  - Faculty: articles and correspondence (Box 24, Folder 158)
  - Faculty: Jesse Weekes (Box 24, Folder 159)
  - Faculty: Dr. Thomson and Canton Hospital (Box 24, Folder 160)
  - Articles about University and Canton (Box 24, Folder 161)
- Hmong (Miao) People Research Materials, Series VI
  - Notes and collected material
    - Research Proposal: Miao in China, 1987-1988 (Box 40, Folder 438)
    - Ding, Phillip (Box 29, Folder 217)
    - Folktale (S.W. China) Contacts--Professors Hoang and Guo (Kunming), 1987 (Box 29, Folder 218)
    - Gong Zhe-Bing: Miao Research, S.W. China (Box 29, Folder 219)
    - Gong Zhe-Bing: student field tests (Box 29, Folder 220)
    - A Happy People--the Miaos, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 221)
    - Chinese photo book (Box 29, Folder 222)
    - Hmong/Miao issue (as name) (Box 30, Folder 223)
    - Research notes (Box 30, Folder 224)
    - Audio cassette tapes, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 224A)
    - Photos: Hunan and Guizho, Fenghuan, Shanjiang, Quiantong, Gao Zai (Box 30, Folder 225)
    - Report to SARS--Hunan (Box 30, Folder 226)
    - SRM notes on visits to Miao Communities in S.W. China, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 227)
    - Nicholas Tapp: Conference on Ethnicity and Ethnic Groups in China, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 228)
    - Xu Xiao-Yi, Huaxi Hotel, Miao Research, S.W. China (Box 30, Folder 229)
  - Articles re. Hmong (Miao)
    - Inez de Beauclair, "A Miao Tribe of Southeast Kweichow and its Cultural Configuration", 1970 (Box 30, Folder 230)
    - Geo. Edgar Betts, "Social Life of the Miao Tsi", 1899 (Box 30, Folder 231)
    - A Bibliography of the Hmong (Miao), 1983 (Box 30, Folder 232)
    - John Blofeld, "Some Hilltribes of North Thailand (Miaos and Yaos)" (Box 30, Folder 233)
    - B. Bourotte, "Mariages et funerailles chez les Meo blancs de la region de Nong-Het (Tran Ninh)", 1943 (Box 30, Folder 234)
    - Norma Diamond, "The Miao and Poison: Interactions on China's Southwest Frontier", 1988 (Box 30, Folder 235)
    - Rev. J. Edkins, "The Miau Tsi Tribes: Their History", 1870 (Box 30, Folder 236)
    - Fei Xiaotong, "Revisiting the Mountains of the Yao People", 1979 (Box 30, Folder 237)
    - W. R. Geddes, "Opium and the Miao: a Study in Ecological Adjustment", 1970 (Box 30, Folder 238)
    - Hmong/Miao in China and SEA and Australia (Box 30, Folder 239)
    - A.L. Kroeber, "Miao and Chinese Kin Logic", 1958 (Box 30, Folder 240)
    - Frank M. Labor, ed., "Miao-Yao" in Ethnic Groups of Mainland Southeast Asia, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 241)
    - Lin Yueh-Hwa, "The Miao-Man Peoples of Kweichow", 1941 (Box 30, Folder 242)
    - Liu Chungshee Hsien, "The Dog-Ancestor Story of the Aboriginal Tribes of Southern China", 1932 (Box 30, Folder 243)
    - Miao in China (Box 31, Folder 244)
    - The Mien, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 245)
    - J. Mottin, "History of the Hmong" (Box 31, Folder 246)
    - Ruey Yih-Fu, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 247)
    - Ruey Yih-Fu, "The Magpie Miao of Southern Szechuan", 1960 (Box 31, Folder 248)
    - Ruey Yih-Fu, "A Study of the Miao People", 1967 (Box 31, Folder 249)
    - Ruey Yih-Fu, "Terminological Structure of the Miao Kinship System", 1958 (Box 31, Folder 250)
    - F.M. Savina, Histoire des Miao, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 251)
    - Robert Shafer, "Classification of the Sino-Tibetan Languages", 1955 (Box 31, Folder 252)
    - Y. Shiratori, "Concerning the Racial and Cultural Relation of the Miao", 1960 (Box 31, Folder 253)
- Presbyterian Mission Home (Cameron House), San Francisco Research Materials, 1991; Series VII
  - Matthew Fong, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 254)
  - Red notebook: A - Cameron (Box 31, Folder 255)
  - Blue notebook (Box 31, Folder 256)
  - M. Peterson--San Francisco Theological Seminary (Box 31, Folder 257)
  - Liang May Seen: influence on descendants (Box 31, Folder 258)
  - Colleen Fong, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 259)
  - Qui Fah, 1892 (Box 31, Folder 260)
  - Misc. Notes (Box 31, Folder 261)
  - Chinese prostitutes (Chuck and Logan) (Box 31, Folder 262)
  - Cameron House Papers (Box 31, Folder 263)
  - "The Influence of San Francisco's Presbyterian Mission Home on the Chinese Women Residents of the Home and Their Descendants", 1995 (Box 31, Folder 264)
  - Research Paper on Cameron House--HK Conference and Publication (includes floppy disk) (Box 32, Folder 265)
  - Cameron House papers (includes floppy disc), 1991-1996 (Box 38, Folder 388)
  - Articles on Cameron House (Box 38, Folder 389)
  - Zed Press References for Chinese Patriarchy (Box 32, Folder 266)
  - Cameron House--recent programs (Box 32, Folder 267)
  - Ernest Wu/Cameron House (Box 32, Folder 268)
  - Pastor Harry Chuck, Margaret, and Liang May Seen (Box 32, Folder 269)
  - Photographs and Slides--Cameron House (Box 32, Folder 270)
  - Interview tapes: Lorna Logan, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 271)
  - Lorna E. Logan, Ventures in Mission: the Cameron House Story, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 272)
  - Lorna Logan (Box 32, Folder 273)
  - Cameron House and Lorna Logan (Box 32, Folder 274)
  - Lorna Logan PHS (Box 32, Folder 275)
  - Arthur Brown on Donaldina Cameron, 1932 (Box 32, Folder 276)
  - Mildred Crowl Martin, Chinatown's Angry Angel: the Story of Donaldina Cameron, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 277)
  - McClain, "D. Cameron: a Reappraisal", 1983 (Box 32, Folder 278)
  - Misc. D. Cameron Documents (Box 32, Folder 279)
  - Mildred Martin on Cameron, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 280)
  - Carol Green Wilson, Chinatown Quest: One Hundred Years of Donaldina Cameron House 1874-1974 (Box 33, Folder 281)
  - Peggy Pascoe, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 282)
  - Margaret Culbertson (Box 33, Folder 283)
  - Donaldina Cameron and Tien Wu data--PHS (Box 33, Folder 284)
  - Muriel Wing (Box 33, Folder 285)
  - Tien Fuh Wu (Box 33, Folder 286)
  - Martha Yick: New York Chinatown funeral director (Box 33, Folder 287)
  - Julia Morgan (Box 33, Folder 288)
  - May Wong PHS (Box 33, Folder 289)
  - The Occident: Ng Poon Chew and Chun Fah, 1892-1893 (Box 33, Folder 290)
  - Rev. Ng Poon-Chew, "Mission Work Among the Chinese in San Francisco", 1909 (Box 33, Folder 291)
  - San Francisco Chinatown Christians (Box 33, Folder 292)
  - E.V. Robbins, "Our Forty Years: 1873-1913" (Box 33, Folder 293)
  - Pauline Robbins (Box 33, Folder 294)
  - Article on Mission Home, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 295)
  - The Occident: "A Bit of Romance at '920' [Cameron House]", 1900 (Box 33, Folder 296)
  - Eva Clark Waid, "At Work Among the Chinese in America" (Box 33, Folder 297)
  - Donaldina Cameron, "New Lives for Old in Chinatown", 1934 (Box 33, Folder 298)
  - "Register of Inmates" 1877-1900's: vol. 1 (Box 33, Folder 299)
  - "Register of Inmates" 1877-1900's: vol. 2 (Box 33, Folder 300)
  - "Register of Inmates" 1877-1900's: vol. 3 (Box 33, Folder 301)
  - Charles R. Shepherd, "Chinese Girl Slavery in America", 1923 (Box 33, Folder 302)
  - Lucie Cheng Hirata, "Free, Indentured, Enslaved: Chinese Prostitutes in Nineteenth Century America", 1979 (Box 33, Folder 303)
  - Bibliography on White Slavery and Women (Box 33, Folder 304)
  - Charles Frederick Holder, "Chinese Slavery in America", 1897 (Box 33, Folder 305)
  - Elizabeth Andrew and Katherine Bushnell, "Heathen Slaves and Christian Rulers", 1907 (Box 33, Folder 306)
  - The Chinese Recorder (Box 33, Folder 307)
  - C. Bruce Staiger, "Abolitionism and the Presbyterian Schism of 1837-1838" (Box 34, Folder 308)
  - Presbyterian Church in Chinatown: 120th Anniversary Report (1853-1973) (Box 34, Folder 309)
  - Chinese Church in U.S.A. (Box 34, Folder 310)
  - Chinese Presbyterian Church, School, etc., in San Francisco, 1866 (Box 34, Folder 311)
  - S.F. Theological Sem.: M. Peterson (Box 34, Folder 312)
  - Documentation: PHS (Box 34, Folder 313)
  - Presbyterian Historical Society (Box 34, Folder 314)
  - Presbyterian Societies (Box 34, Folder 315)
  - Clifford Merrill Drury, "Presbyterian Panorama", 1952 (Box 34, Folder 316)
  - Pearl Ng: Bibliography on Chinese in California (Box 34, Folder 317)
  - John K. C. Liu, Christopher L. Yip, and Sara Ishikawa, "San Francisco Chinatown and its Residential Hotels: the Everyday Environment of the Chinese-American Elderly", 1980 (Box 34, Folder 318)
  - Annie Soo, "Chinese Settlement at Columbia" (Box 34, Folder 319)
  - Suellen Cheng, "A Report on the Southern California Chinese American Oral History Project", 1980 (Box 34, Folder 320)
  - Loh, Homer Ch'i Ch'en (Box 34, Folder 321)
  - Philadelphia Chinatown (Box 34, Folder 322)
  - Chinese in U.S.--Bibliography (Box 34, Folder 323)
  - Rose Hum Lee, "Chinese Christian Churches", "The Decline of Chinatowns in the United States" (Box 34, Folder 324)
  - Chinese in Arizona (Box 34, Folder 325)
  - Dennis Loo, "Why an Asian American Theology of Liberation?", 1974 (Box 34, Folder 326)
  - Delia Wong Stephens, "Chinese-Americans in Kansas City", 1980 (Box 34, Folder 327)
  - Chinese in U.S.: women, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 328)
  - James W. Loewen, "The Mississippi Chinese: Between Black and White", 1971 (Box 34, Folder 329)
  - Stanford M. Lyman, "Social Demography of the Chinese and Japanese in the U.S. of America", 1970 (Box 34, Folder 330)
  - Grant K. Anderson, "Deadwood's China", 1975 (Box 34, Folder 331)
  - Edward J.M. Rhoads, "The Chinese in Texas" (Box 34, Folder 332)
  - Chinese in New York City (Box 34, Folder 333)
  - Daniel Liestman, "'To Win Redeemed Souls from Heathen Darkness': Protestant Response to the Chinese of the Pacific Northwest in the Late Nineteenth Century", 1993 (Box 34, Folder 334)
  - Chinese-American Family Structure (Box 34, Folder 335)
  - Chinese in U.S.: miscellaneous (Box 34, Folder 336)
  - Colloquium on Overseas Chinese, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 337)
  - Sue Fawn Chung, "A Brief History of the Chinese in Nevada", 1980 (Box 34, Folder 338)
  - Chinese in Hawaii (Box 34, Folder 339)
  - National Archives (Box 35, Folder 340)
  - John S. Mosby and David Bailey: letters (Box 35, Folder 341)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Index of Contents (Box 35, Folder 342)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 1-6, 1874-1879 (Box 35, Folder 343)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 7-12, 1880-1885 (Box 35, Folder 344)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 13, 1886 (Box 35, Folder 345)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 14-16, 1887-1889 (Box 35, Folder 346)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 19, 1892 (Box 35, Folder 347)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 20-26, 1893-1899 (Box 35, Folder 348)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 27-30, 1900-1903 (Box 35, Folder 349)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 31-34, 1904-1907 (Box 36, Folder 350)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 35-38, 1908-1911 (Box 36, Folder 351)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 39, 41-46, 1912-1919 (Box 36, Folder 352)
  - Reports of the Women's Occidental Board of Foreign Missions: Annual Report: 47, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 353)
- Henry and Sarah F. Refo Family Papers, 1978-1983; Series VIII
  - Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 24, Folder 162)
  - Photos (Box 24, Folder 163a)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1988 (Box 25, Folder 163b)
  - Sarah F. Refo documents and biographical information (Box 25, Folder 164)
  - Sarah F. Refo letters (Box 25, Folder 165)
  - Confession of Faith (Box 25, Folder 166)
  - Correspondence of Henry Refo, 1950s (Box 25, Folder 167)
  - Letters from China of Sarah F. Refo-Published, 1917-1948 (Box 25, Folder 168)
  - Sarah F. Refo letters, 1918-1921 (Box 25, Folder 169-171)
  - Sarah F. Refo letters, 1940-1959 (Box 26, Folder 172)
  - Muriel Lockwood Refo interview for Midwest Oral Project, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 173)
  - Henry Refo-letters and documents (Box 26, Folder 174)
  - Henry Refo interview for Midwest Oral Project, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 175)
  - Correspondence with Chinese Employees of Refo's in the 1930s, Ah Laan and Ah Tuen (Box 26, Folder 176)
  - WWII clippings and Prisoner Repatriation Lists (Box 26, Folder 177)
  - Missionary holiday camps - Loh fau and Laan tau Island (Box 26, Folder 178)
- Re. life and work of Sarah Refo Mason, Series IX
  - Biographical documentation
    - Chronology of SRM's life, CVs; autobiographical statement re. background for research on missionary children. (Box 40, Folder 444)
    - Trips to China: notes and letters; article by Mason's daughter Rachel describing 1996 trip with Mason to bring home adopted Chinese daughter, 1982, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 445)
    - Zhongshan University Visit (Box 40, Folder 446)
    - Notes and Journals at Zhongshan University: part 1, 1986-1987 (Box 41, Folder 447)
    - Notes and Journals at Zhongshan University: part 2, 1986-1987 (Box 41, Folder 448)
    - Notes and Journals at Zhongshan University: part 3, 1986-1987 (Box 41, Folder 449)
    - Notes (Box 41, Folder 450)
    - Senior paper topics/grades (Box 41, Folder 451)
    - Student papers (Box 41, Folder 452)
    - Students of Sarah R. Mason (Box 41, Folder 453)
    - Guangzhou Foreign Languages Institute, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 454)
    - Zhou Xing-ying (Box 41, Folder 455)
    - Li Jiefang (Box 41, Folder 456)
    - Reference Letter, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 457)
    - Professor Hu Jing Zhao, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 458)
    - Chen Na-fu, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 459)
  - Papers, publications, and presentations by SRM
    - "Protestant Liberals and Conservatives Among the China Missionaries: a Comparison of Religious Values and Cultural Interaction", 1977 (Box 37, Folder 372)
    - "Women's Role in Two Korean United Methodist Congregations in Minnesota: Shaping the Church to Mutual Support and Ethnic Solidarity", 1980 (Box 37, Folder 373)
    - "Family Structure and Acculturation in Minnesota's Chinese and Filipino Communities", 1979 (Box 37, Folder 374)
    - Methodist Women's Conference, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 375)
    - "Family Structure and Acculturation in the Chinese Community in Minnesota", 1980 (Box 37, Folder 376)
    - Lecture notes for Augsburg College, "Sisterhood of the Faith: Missionary Women and their Christian Converts in Early Twentieth Century China", 1982 (Box 37, Folder 377)
    - "Liberating Chinese Womanhood: a Case Study in Missionary Feminism and Evangelism, 1915-1922", 1981 (Box 37, Folder 378)
    - "Training Asian Women for Employment" (Box 26, Folder 179)
    - National Women's Studies Association (Box 37, Folder 379)
    - Berkshire Conference (Box 37, Folder 380)
    - "Kinship, Community, and the Welfare State Public Policy and Hmong Families in St. Paul and Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 381)
    - History of Christianity in China Grant, 1989-1990 (Box 38, Folder 382)
    - Minnesota Historical Society Women's History Grants Program, 1991-1992 (Box 38, Folder 383)
    - "They Chose Minnesota: a Survey of the State's Ethnic Groups", 1981 (Box 38, Folder 384)
    - "Identity and Social Conscience: the Role of Missionary Sons and Daughters in United States-China Relations, 1900-1949" (Box 38, Folder 385)
    - Program of the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Asian Studies, Inc., 1990 (Box 38, Folder 386)
    - AAS Conference, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 387)
    - Minnesota Historical Society Program, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 390)
  - Midwest China Study Resource Center--Oral History Project
    - Interviews, committee meetings, misc. correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 42, Folder 460)
    - Benedictine Sisters (Box 42, Folder 461)
    - Myron S. Burton (Box 42, Folder 462)
    - Rev. Earl Dahlstron (Box 42, Folder 463)
    - Ella and Clemens Granskou (Box 42, Folder 464)
    - Beatrice Liu (Box 42, Folder 465)
    - Ingeborg Stolee (Box 42, Folder 466)
    - Borghilde Syrdal (Box 42, Folder 467)
    - Rolf A. Syrdal (Box 42, Folder 468)
    - Josef Wang (Box 42, Folder 469)
    - Lutheran Literature Society for the Chinese (Box 42, Folder 470)
  - Correspondence with colleagues and others
    - Daniel Bays (Box 38, Folder 391)
    - Peggy Bell, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 392)
    - Hy Berman (Box 38, Folder 393)
    - Alice M. Carpenter (Box 38, Folder 394)
    - Alice Chai (Box 38, Folder 394A)
    - Winnie (Chu) and Gilbert Chan (Box 38, Folder 395)
    - Chen Sheng (Box 38, Folder 396)
    - Cheng Shujian (Box 38, Folder 397)
    - Winnie Chu (Box 38, Folder 398)
    - Joe Cunneen (Box 38, Folder 399)
    - Roger Daniels (Box 38, Folder 400)
    - Mariam Frenier (Box 38, Folder 401)
    - Fu Sai Si (Box 38, Folder 402)
    - Mary Furner (Box 38, Folder 403)
    - Jon Gjerde (Box 39, Folder 404)
    - Goo Gwei-Tsing and Van (Box 39, Folder 405)
    - Sue Gronewald (Box 39, Folder 406)
    - Susanna Hoe (Box 39, Folder 407)
    - Jerry Israel (Box 39, Folder 408)
    - Douglas Lee and Russell Leong (Box 39, Folder 409)
    - Li Jie Fang and Ziang Xiang-zhe (Box 39, Folder 410)